# MICHAEL Z WANG

# WEB DEVELOPER

## ABOUT ME

I am a junior web developer with prior experience in biological research. I love working on websites and being able to see my work appear on screen. Currently, I am interested in opportunities that will allow me to work and learn in a collaborative environment.

### SKILLS

**LANGUAGES** 

Ruby Rails
JavaScript Sinatra
jQuery Git / GitHub

FRAMEWORKS / SERVICES

SQL Heroku
HTML5 RSpec
CSS3 / SASS Capybara
ActiveRecord BigCommerce

## **PROJECTS**

#### Loopi

Web app that provides users with customizable running routes based on the user's location and desired run length. Each route is a unique loop that begins and ends at the user's location.

- · Built using Rails and Javascript over an 8-day period.
- Utilized the Geokit gem to retrieve geolocation coordinate data.
- Manipulated Google Maps API to take data outputted by Geokit and create waypoints for a route with turn-by-turn directions.

#### **Boba Finds Tea**

A social media web app designed for boba tea lovers to share opinions about their drinks. With this app users can discover, rate and post about tea cafes.

- Built using Ruby, JavaScript and Sinatra over a 3-day period.
- Used Google Maps API to search for and display a cafe based on a street address

## **EDUCATION**

**Dev Bootcamp** 

Software Development Intensive 2016

University of California, Berkeley BA Integrative Biology 2014 GPA 3.852

## **EXPERIENCE**

Cocoweb Irvine, CA
Web Development & Design Intern Nov 2016 - Current

- Coordinate with on-site teams to improve website brand and improve functionality and profitability for the online webstore.
- Gained experience in web design, web development, marketing, graphics, and e-commerce operations through maintenance of product offerings on website and implementation of new services for interior designers.

Dev Bootcamp Web Developer Graduate San Diego, CA Dec 2015 - Apr 2016

- Completed an 19-week intensive course comprising 1000+ hours learning Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, HTML5/CSS3, and accompanying tools and frameworks.
- Focused on emotional intelligence, teamwork, diversity training, and conflict management through pair programming and group projects.
- Co-created Loopi, a web app that generates randomized running routes based on location and desired distance.

#### Polaris Pharmaceuticals

San Diego, CA Sep 2014 - Sep 2015

Research Assistant

 Worked independently and with a team to study and analyze the role of aspartate transcarbamylase (ATCase) in cancer cell growth.

San Francisco General Hospital

San Francisco, CA Jan 2013 - May 2014

• Educated families about medical care, food, employment, and legal aid and walked them through processes like applying for benefits.

**UC Berkeley** 

Berkeley, CA

Research Assistant

Jun 2012 - May 2014

 Studied the Wnt-5a protein pathway to elucidate its role during inflammation and lymphangiogenesis.

International Service Learning

Berkeley, CA

**UC Berkeley Representative** 

Jan 2012 - May 2014

 Recruited new members and prepared them for future medical service trips in Central America.